Guide to the John Hersey Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- March 1992 Acquisition, 1917-1990; 46.63; (54 boxes)
  - Committee Reports and Other Material
    - The Call, notes, research material (partial) and correspondence, 1980-1986; 14 (Box 61)
    - Unidentified correspondence and articles, 1954-1955
    - Blues, first and second drafts, research, reviews, 1987; 4 (Box 61)
    - Blues, drafts, autograph manuscript, master galley and proof pages, 1987; 15 (Box 62)
    - Fling, submitted copy, master galleys, 1990; 2 (Box 62)
    - Hiroshima, notes, research and correspondence, 1985; 9 (Box 63)
    - "China," notes, research, proofs and correspondence, 1982; 12 (Box 63)
    - Fairfield School Study Council, report on reading, related material, 1954 (Box 64)
    - Printed material, 1950-1980 (Box 64)
    - Printed material (continued), 1950-1980; 5 (Box 65)
  - Oversize
    - Men on Bataan, scrapbook, 1942 (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - The Wall, review, New York Times Book Review, 1950 February 26 (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - "Year of the Triphammer", 1978 (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - "China," page proofs, 1982 (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - Into the Valley, empty scrapbook, 1943 February (Box 67 (Oversize))
  - Restricted Fragile Material
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Westport Connecticut Democratic Town Committee, Rules, 1949 (Box 68)
    - Writers' Board for World Government; Myth, That Threatens the World, 1949 (Box 68)
    - Unidentified correspondence and articles, 1954-1955 (Box 68)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, 27; 27 audiotape reels and 1 case (Box 69)
      - Sortor, February 18; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979121)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Sorter-Paille, February 18; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979345)
      - August, 1968 February 19; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979303)
      - August #1, 1968 February 19; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979220)
      - August #2, 1968 February 19; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979212)
      - Paille, February 19; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979295)
      - Senak, February 20; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979279)
      - Senak #2, 1968 February 25; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979261)
      - Senak #1, February 25; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979113)
      - Senak #3, 1968 February 25; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979105)
      - Senak #4, February 25; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979097)
      - Senak #5, 1968 February 25; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979311)
      - Tape #6, Al Dunmore, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979154)
      - Tape #7, February 5; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979287)
      - Tape #8, Eddie Temple / Leon Atchism, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979329)
      - Tape #9, Omar Gill; Mrs. Cooper, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979162)
      - Tape #10, Sortor 1 + 2, November 13; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979253)
      - Tape #12, Robt, Mrs. P, Thelma, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979352)
      - Tape #13, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979188)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979139)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979147)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979246)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979196)
      - #3, Tanner, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979170)
      - Leon Atchism, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979204)
      - One side 2, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979238)
      - Mrs. Pollard 2, undated; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979337)
    - Hiroshima, The Drama Department in collaboration with the Noyes' Theater in the Round, 1965 November 14; 1 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002109979089)
    - Ralph Ellison, undated (Box 70)
      4 2.5" reel-to-reel audiotapes
      - Ellison #1, undated; 1 (Box 70, Item barcode 39002109977596)
      - Ellison #2, undated; 1 (Box 70, Item barcode 39002109977604)
      - Ellison #3, undated; 1 (Box 70, Item barcode 39002109977612)
      - Ellison #4, undated; 1 (Box 70, Item barcode 39002109977620)
    - Life Magazine, articles, undated (Box 70)
      19 6" SoundScriber discs
    - The President, undated; (5 audiocassettes) (Box 71)
      - #1, GF Breakfast, Thurs, March 13; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002109977547)
      - #2, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002109977554)
      - #3, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002109977562)
      - #4, Runs over on other side, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002109977570)
      - #5, Finished, undated; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002109977588)
- October 2013 Acquisition, circa 1930s-1992; 3.5; (13 Boxes)
  This acquisition consists of correspondence, datebooks, photographs, writings, audio tape and other papers by or relating to John Hersey.
  Gift of Brook Hersey, 2013.
  - Correspondence, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 95)
    Barbara Kaufman/Hersey, Yale students and others.
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 96)
    Yale Students
  - Correspondence and passports, 1940s-1980s (Box 97)
    Yale Students correspondence.
  - Datebooks, 1944-1952 (Box 98)
  - Datebooks, 1953-1969 (Box 99)
  - Datebooks, 1970-1983 (Box 100)
  - Datebooks, 1984-1990 (Box 101)
  - Correspondence, circa 1992 (Box 102)
    Condolence letters on the death of John Hersey to Barbara Hersey, by author A to G.
  - Correspondence, circa 1992 (Box 103)
    Condolence letters on the death of John Hersey to Barbara Hersey, by author H to Z.
  - Writings, correspondence and photographic portraits, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 104)
  - Proofs, The President, circa 1975 (Box 105)
  - Photographs, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 106)
  - Interview with John Cheever for The New York Times (audiocassette), circa 1950-1970; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109979360)
    Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - David Hilliard at Ingall's Rink (audiotape reel), 1970 April 21; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109979378)
- August 2014 Acquisitions, 1917-1992; 9.09; (23 boxes)
  Gift of Brook Hersey, 2014.
  These acquisitions consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, and printed materials by or relating to John Hersey.
  - Letter File Box 46, 1940s-1960s; (6 folders) (Box 72)
    Proffesional and academic correspondence.
  - Carton 17, 1917-1960; (5 folders) (Box 72)
    Personal and family business material including correspondence, greeting cards, certifications and legal documents.
  - Letter File Box No. 66, 1934-1937; 3 folders (Box 72)
    Notes, personal and school papers.
  - Photographs, 1946-1990 (Box 73)
  - Photographs, 1930-1953 (Box 73)
  - Photographs, 1953-1984 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1981; 2 folders (Box 74)
  - Correspondence from Carton 18, 1976-1981; 2 folders (Box 74)
  - Time Inc., 1938-1968; 2 folders (Box 75)
  - China Correspondence, 1925-1985 (Box 75)
  - Writings, Undated (Box 75)
  - Antonietta, 1991 (Box 76)
  - Plastic file case carton 17, 1963-1979; 2 folders (Box 76)
    Writings
  - Plastic file case carton 17, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 77)
  - Contracts, 1959-1976 (Box 77)
  - Letter File Box 5, 1946 (Box 77)
  - Letter File Box 5, 1946-1991; 2 folders (Box 78)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983; 3 folders (Box 78)
    A to G
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983; 5 folders (Box 79)
    H to Z
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 80)
    New Yorker
  - Notes, Undated; 2 folders (Box 80)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 80)
  - Antonietta Research, Undated; 6 folders (Box 81)
  - Antonietta Research, Undated; 5 folders (Box 82)
  - Antonietta: Correspondence, Reviews, etc., 1989-1992; 3 folders (Box 83)
  - Short Stories, 1987-1990; 3 folders (Box 84)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 84)
  - Notes, Interview, Writings, 1986 (Box 84)
  - Writings, 1966-1986 (Box 84)
  - Yale Correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 85)
  - Correspondence about Books, 1956-1991 (Box 85)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 85)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1987 (Box 85)
  - Writings, 1987-1989 (Box 85)
  - Moscow, 1987 (Box 85)
  - Writings, 1987-1988 (Box 85)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1965-1972 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1991; 4 folders (Box 86)
  - The Call: Correspondence, Reviews, and other materials, 1985-1988 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1991 (Box 87)
  - Authors Guild, 1939-1965 (Box 87)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945 (Box 87)
  - Russia, 1944; 2 folders (Box 87)
  - Russia, 1944 (Box 88)
  - Notes, Russia, Undated; 3 folders (Box 88)
  - Notes and other materials, 1944-1982 (Box 88)
    No Subnote Content
  - Correspondence, circa 1970-1991 (Box 89)
  - Correspondence and Reviews, 1966-1993 (Box 89)
  - Magazines, 1983-1989 (Box 89)
  - Publications, 1983-1987 (Box 90)
  - Publications, 1987-1989 (Box 90)
  - War Correspondence, Writings, 1943 (Box 90)
  - War Photographs, Maps, Undated (Box 90)
  - War Correspondence, 1943 (Box 90)
  - War Correspondence, Undated (Box 90)
  - War Momentos, 1942 (Box 90)
    Notebooks and identification
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 90)
  - Correspondence, Writings, 1983-1992; 3 folders (Box 91)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1985; 3 folders (Box 91)
  - Correspondence, Writings, 1973-1985; 3 folders (Box 92)
  - Key West Tales, Undated (Box 92)
  - Key West Tales, Correspondence, 1981-1992 (Box 92)
  - Photograph Portraits, 1985 (Box 92)
  - Notes, writings, childhood materials, circa 1914-1991 (Box 93)
  - Life Magazine proofs, degrees and awards, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 94)